Miscellaneous Art Exhibition Catalog Collection
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Miscellaneous art exhibition catalog collection
1813-1953, bulk 1915-1925
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Archives of American Art
4.4 linear feet
Primarily exhibition catalogs for modernist art exhibitions held in New York City during the first two decades of the twentieth century. Also included are catalogs for Boston exhibitions, mainly pre-1900, and a few other locales; exhibition announcements; gallery publications; and other printed material.
Historical Note
In 1979, the American Antiquarian Society donated approximately 1,500 exhibition catalogs and art-related printed material to the Archives of American Art (AAA). The Society had received most of them over a long period of time, many of them addressed to the director, Charles Brigham. For several years subsequent to the donation, AAA sporadically added exhibition catalogs to the collection from various sources. Some of these additions are annotated in the hand of Walt Kuhn and are presumed to have been part of his papers in the Archives.
Scope and Content Note
The collection comprises circa 770 items, dating from 1813-1953, the bulk of which are exhibition catalogs from New York City art galleries for the first two decades of the twentieth century, representing exhibitions of mainly modernist art. Catalogs for exhibitions held in Boston (mainly pre-1900) and a few other cities are also present. Included are several rare catalogs, notably one for the "Eight" held at Macbeth Gallery in 1908. Besides catalogs, the collection also contains exhibition announcements, gallery publications, and other printed material. The collection is especially relevant for the study of early American modernism, and is useful in understanding the role of art galleries, exhibitions, the art market, and the exhibition catalog itself, in American art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series representing alphabetical groups. Catalogs are arranged within these groups according to name of the sponsoring gallery, or if no gallery is listed, by the name of the club or organization. Catalogs are arranged chronologically thereafter, with undated material first. Many catalogs are undated, list only a year, or are annotated with a date. No attempt has been made to date or verify these at this time. Catalogs which are annotated with a date are filed chronologically, and are indicated with brackets around the date.
Series 1: Art Exhibition Catalogs, A-C
Series 2: Art Exhibition Catalogs, D-F
Series 3: Art Exhibition Catalogs, G-I
Series 4: Art Exhibition Catalogs, J-L
Series 5: Art Exhibition Catalogs, M-O
Series 6: Art Exhibition Catalogs, P-R
Series 7: Art Exhibition Catalogs, S-T
Series 8: Art Exhibition Catalogs, U-Z
Related Material
Researchers may find duplicate or related items in galleries' records held at the Archives of American Art. Additional or duplicate catalogs may appear in AAA's Catalog of Exhibition Catalogs (1979).
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Modernism (Art) -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions; Art, Modern -- 20th century -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions; Art, Modern -- 19th century -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions; Art, Modern -- 19th century -- Massachusetts -- Exhibitions; Art, American -- Exhibitions; Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State) -- New York; Art galleries, Commercial -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Artists -- United States -- Exhibitions
Types of Materials:
Exhibition catalogs
Names:
Kuhn, Walt, 1877-1949
Provenance
The bulk of the collection was donated 1979 by the American Antiquarian Society, who presumably assembled them from various sources. Others were received individually, while many are annotated in the hand of Walt Kuhn and are presumed to have originally been part of his papers in the Archives. In 2005, additional catalogs were integrated, some of which are presumed to have been removed from various collections over the years.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of this collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 4858-4859 at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Art Exhibition Catalogs: A-C, Series 1:
  - ACA Gallery, 52 West 8th Street, New York City (Box 1)
    - 1938 Dedicated to the New Deal, circa 1938 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Artists in the War, June 14, 1942 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Artists' Tribute in Memory of Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1947 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Ainslie Galleries, 615 Fifth Ave. and 677 Fifth Ave., New York City (Box 1)
    - Exhibition of Paintings by Emma Fordyce MacRae (Mrs. Homer F. Swift), November 16-30 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings and Sculpture by Anna Vaughn Hyatt, Graze P. Noxon, Jane Peterson, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Heppie En Earl Wicks, January 3-February 3, 1922 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Alexander O. Levy, December 15-31, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Water Colors by Isabel L. Whitney, March 16-28, 1925 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Albert Roullie Art Galleries, 414 South Michigan Boulevard, Chicago (Box 1)
    - Original Etchings and Lithographs by Albert Sterner, May 13-31, 1930 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Alpine Club Gallery, London, England (Box 1)
    - Grafton Group Exhibition, March 15-31, 1913 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - American Abstract Artists (Box 1)
    - American Abstract Artists, 1938 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - American Art Galleries, Madison Square South, New York City (Box 1)
    - The Seney Collection, March 31-April 2, 1885 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Collection of George I Seney, February 11-13, 1891 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Private Art Collection of Thomas B. Clarke, February 14-17, 1899 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Twachtman Sale, March 24, 1903 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Paintings and Water Colors by and Belonging to Samuel Colman, N.A., March 25, 1903 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Private Collection of the Late Frederick S. Gibbs, February 24-26, 1904 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Finished Pictures Left by the Late Walter Clark, N.A., March 4, 1918 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Paintings and Drawings by J. Francis Murphy, November 20-26, 1926 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - The Stillman Collection of Paintings, January 29-February 3, 1927 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - John Quinn Collection, February 5-9, 1927 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - John Quinn Collection Sale, February 9, 1927 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Oil Paintings, Water Colors by Leading American Contemporaries, The Collection of Dr. Thomas L. Bennett, December 3-7, 1927 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - The Library and Autograph Collection of the Late Thomas B. Clarke, December 3, 1931 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - American Landscapes: The Private Collection of Burton Mansfield, April 7, 1933 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Oil Paintings, Etchings, Drawings, Lithographs Including Two Important Ryders From the Estate of Newman E. Montross, April 20, 1933 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - American Artist Congress (Box 1)
    - First American Artists Congress, 1936 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - American Artists Exhibition, April 16-29, 1937 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - An Exhibition in Defense of World Democracy, December 15-30, 1937 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - American Artists Congress Annual Exhibition, May 5-21, 1938 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Third Annual Membership Exhibition, February 5-26, 1939 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Fourth Annual Membership Exhibition, April 6-28, 1940 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Fourth American Writers Congress in Defense of Culture and Congress of American Artists, June 6-8, 1941 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - An American Group Inc., 50 Charles Street, New York City (Box 1)
    - First Annual Exhibition: Watercolors, Gouaches and Small Sculptures, circa 1941 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Roofs for 40 million: An Exhibition on Housing, April 9-May 1, [1936-7] (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - American Woman's Art Association of Paris, Paris, France (Box 1)
    - Catalogue of the American Woman's Art Association, February 12-28, 1910 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Anderson Galleries, Park Ave. and 59th St., New York City (Box 1)
    - [Invitation] "Hands across the Gulf Stream... to meet Frueh & Massaguer..." Caricature by Fornaro, December 19, [1921?] (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - [Invitation] "Come and See My Babies-Clara Tice", November 17-December 1 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Special Exhibitions [includes Roderick D. Mackenzie, Emil Orlik, Alice Judson, and W. Sherman Potts], February 19-March 1 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - An Exhibition of the Work of Bradley Walker Tomlin, March 4-17 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Catalog of an Exhibition of One Hundred Oil Paintings by Louis Rhead of American Marine and Freshwater Gamefish in their Native Habitat, March 18-29 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Association of Women Painters and Sculptors - Twenty-fourth Annual Exhibition, April 5-17, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - The Forum Exhibition of Modern American Painters, March 13-25, 1916 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Sky Fighters of France, March 10-20, 1918 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - An Exhibition of Photography by Alfred Stieglitz, February 7, [1921] (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors Thirtieth Annual Exhibition 1921, February 23-March 15, 1921 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Wood-Engravings, Etchings, and Drawings by Rudolph Ruzicka, November 28 - December 10, 1921 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - A Collection of Works by Living American Artists of the Modern Schools, February 23, 1922 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Ethel Wallace Textile and Decorative paintings, March 20-April 2, 1922 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors Thirty-First Annual Exhibition 1922, April 4-15, 1922 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - 1922 Autumn Salon [Salons of America, Inc.], October 16-November 4, 1922 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Paintings by Abel G. Warshawsky, November 27-December 12, 1922 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - New Society of Artists Fourth Exhibition, January 2-27, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Symbolic Interpretive Paintings by Katharine Whitmarsh, March 4-17, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Second Exhibition of Photography by Alfred Stieglitz, April 2, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Decorative Screens, Panels, Paintings and Stage Designs by John Wenger, May 15-26, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Maine - Recent Etchings by Ernest Haskell, Nov. 5-17, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - New Society of Artists Fifth Exhibition, January 2-31, 1924 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Alfred Stieglitz Presents Fifty-One Recent Pictures - Oils, Watercolors, Pastels, Drawings by Georgia O'Keeffe, American, March 3-16, 1924 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Paintings, Sketches, Etchings, Drawings, and Sculpture by Fifty-Ninth Street Artists, October 6-18, [1924] (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Invitation to the Opening of an Exhibition of Paintings by Olga Szekely-Kovacs, November 9, 1926 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Paintings and Drawings by Richard Wyndham, January 15-22, 1927 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - An Exhibition of Her Work by Lillian V. Gaertner, November 29-December 10, 1927 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Photographs by Rudolf Eickemeyer, February 20-March 4, [1928] (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - [Invitation] Winold Reiss, November 13-25, [1934] (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Arden Gallery, 599 Fifth Ave., New York City (Box 1)
    - Forain and Steinlen Drawings and Lithographs-First American Exhibition, January 14-28, 1919 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Ardsley Studios, 110 Columbia Heights, Brooklyn, NY (Box 1)
    - [Invitation]Exhibition of Paintings and Other Works by a number of Independent Artists,closing October 31, 1918 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - [Invitation]Exhibition of Paintings and Other Works by a number of Modern Artists,closing December 31, 1918 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - [Invitation]Exhibition of Japanese Prints and Paintings and Other Works by a number of Modern Artists,closing January 31, 1919 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - [Invitation]Exhibition of Original Lithographs by Fantin-Latour and Recent Paintings by Alber Gleizes, closing March 31, 1919 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Arlington Galleries, 274 Madison Ave., New York City (Box 1)
    - Paintings by Elizabeth Curtis, April 17-May 8 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Pictures by Maxwell Armfield, February 11-March 2 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings by Belle A. Bennett, Rosemary Mundy, Josephine Thomson, Agnes Louise Symmers, December 1-13 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings by Anna Richards Brewster, February 1-13, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Recent paintings by Helen Watson Phelps, Alice Schille, Adelaide Deming and Emma Lampert Cooper, March 1-13, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings, Landscapes and Portraits by Elizabeth Curtis, April 7-14, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Association of Women Painters and Sculptors Exhibition of Small Pictures and Sculptures, November 20-December 24, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Recent Paintings and Sculptures by Harriette Bowdoin, Edith Penman, Jane Peterson, Alice Preble Tucker De Haas, Agnes M. Richmond, Alethea Hill Platt, Clara T. MacChesney, Clara Davidson Simpson, Harriet W. Frishmuth, January 17-29, 1916 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings by Robert Spencer, A.N.A., November 3-23, 1916 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Association of Women Painters and Sculptors, December 2-24, 1916 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings and Sketches by Matilda Browne, January 31-February 14, 1917 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings in Oil and Tempera by Maxwell Armfield, February 19-March 3, 1917 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - National Association of Women Painters and Sculptors, December 16, 1919-January 3, 1920 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings by Robert Vonnoh, N.A., January 5-22, 1921 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Martha Walter Exhibition, thru February 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Elisha Kent Kane Wetherill Exhibition of American and French Panels and Etchings, thru April 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Art Alliance of America (Box 1)
    - [Invitation] Exhibition of Original Greeting Cards Designed by American Artists, undated (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings and Sculpture by Members of the Art Alliance, March 13-28, 1918 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Portrait Drawings in Three Crayons by Fredrik Theodore Weber, April 15-May 8, 1918 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Art Center, 65-67 E. 56th St., New York City (Box 1)
    - Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture by J. Petria Collin, Emilie Fiero, Alice G. Locke, Anna E. Frost, Frances White, January 15-27 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Photographs by Arnold Genthe, February 10-March 3 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Announcement of opening of new building, October 31, 1921 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Water Color Paintings by Yoshio Markino, April 1-21, 1925 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Art Guild Galleries, 10 East 50th Street, New York City (Box 1)
    - Batik Paintings by Ethel Wallace, April 11-30, 1921 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Arthur H. Hahlo & Co., 569 5th Ave., New York City (Box 1)
    - A New Etching by William Auerbach Levy, undated (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Original Cartoons by Cesare, April 6-17 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - The Etchings of B. J. O. Nordfeldt, undated (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Etchings and Drawings by J. Andre Smith, February 8-27, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Water Colors and Wood Engravings of India, Japan, and the Hawaii Islands by Charles W. Bartlett, March 1-29, 1919 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Art Institute of Chicago (Box 1)
    - L. Moholy: Nagy Exhibition, September 18 - October 26, 1947 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Art Patrons of America (formerly Junior Art Patrons of America), 705 5th Avenue, New York City (Box 1)
    - [Announcement] Pop Hart's Water Colors (Junior Art Patrons), February 19-March 4 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Opening exhibition of the Junior Art Patrons of America, October 10-31, [1921] (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - [Announcement and exhibition listing] Opening of new gallery under direction of Marie Sterner, undated (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Loan Exhibition of Modern Portraits, Painting and Sculpture for the Benefit of the State Charities Aid Association [at the galleries of Jacques Seligmann & Co.], December 1-13 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of American Art [at the Galerie de la Chambre Syndicale des Beaux-Arts, 18 Rue de la Ville-l'Eveque, Paris], June 9-July 5 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - [Annotated price list] Exhibition of American Art [at the Galerie de la Chambre Syndicale des Beaux-Arts, 18 Rue de la Ville-l'Eveque, Paris], June 9-July 5 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Art War Relief, 661 5th Ave., New York City (Box 1)
    - Report of Painter's Committee on Landscape Targets, September 15, 1918 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Artists' Co-operative Galleries, 726 5th Ave., New York City (Box 1)
    - Second Exhibition by the Dialis, A Group of American Painters, December 4-16 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Oil Paintings, February 12-24, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
  - Artists' Fund Society of New York (Box 1)
    - Catalogue of American Paintings and Drawings by F.O.C. Darley, N.A., undated (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Thirteenth Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1873 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of the Thirteenth Annual Sale of Paintings, January 28, 1873 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Fourteenth Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1874 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of the Fifteenth Annual Sale of Paintings, January 26, 1875 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Charter and Constitution, February 9, 1875 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Fifteenth and Sixteenth Annual Reports of the Artists Fund Society, February 9, 1876 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Seventeenth Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1877 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Seventeenth Annual Sale, January 23, 1877 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of the Eighteenth Annual Sale of Paintings, January 22, 1878 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Nineteenth Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1879 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of the Nineteenth Annual Sale of Paintings, January 27-28, 1879 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Twenty-First Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1881 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of the Twenty-Second Annual Sale of Paintings, January 16-17, 1882 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Twenty-Second Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1883 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Twenty-Third Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1883 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Report of the Committee Appointed at the Special Meeting, November 22, 1883 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Twenty-Fourth Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1884 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of the Twenty-Fourth Annual Sale of Paintings, January 15-16, 1884 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Charter and Constitution, 1884 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Twenty-Fifth Annual Report of the Artists Fund Society, 1885 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Charter and Constitution, 1886 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of the Twenty-Eighth Annual Sale of Paintings, undated (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Artists' Galleries, 726 5th Ave., New York City (Box 1)
    - Decorative Flower Paintings by Mrs. Lawrence Wright, May 7-19, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 4858)
    - Report of Activities, Second Season,, 1938 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Arts Club of Chicago (Box 1)
    - Catalogue of an Exhibition of Paintings and Water Colors by Marsden Hartley, February 28- March 13, 1928 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Associated American Artists Galleries (Box 1)
    - Exhibition: Art School Alumni of the Educational Alliance, October 7-22, 1940 (Box 1, Reel unfilmed)
  - Avery Art Galleries, 368 5th Avenue, New York City (Box 2)
    - Exhibition of Works by Elihu Vedder, February 12-24, 1900 (Box 2, Reel unfilmed)
    - Hubert Vos - Later Portraits, March 4-18, [1901] (Box 2, Reel 4858)
  - Babcock Art Galleries, 19 E. 49th St. and 38 E. 57th St., New York City (Box 2)
    - Paintings by the Cosmopolitan Society, January 29 - February 10 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - First Exhibition of the Expressionists, March 1-15 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Annual Exhibition of Paintings of the Southwest by the Taos Society, December 30-January 18 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Recent Paintings by S. Witkewitz, January 16-31 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Exhibition of Paintings Figures on the Sand by Elizabeth W. Roberts, March 4-16 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - The Eclectics Fourth Annual Exhibition, December 2-14, 1918 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - The Eclectics Fifth Annual Exhibition, November 22-December 6, [1919] (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Guild of American Painters, November 29-December 11, 1920 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Recent Paintings by H. Melville Fisher, January 31-February 12, 1921 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Sixth Eclectic Exhibition, February 14-28, 1921 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings of Africa by Leon Tahcheechee, October 22-November 11, 1921 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings by Wharton Harris Esherick, March 28-April 9, 1921 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Guild of American Painters - Annual exhibition, November 28-December 10, 1921 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Birger Sandzen exhibition, 1922 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Eighth Annual Exhibition of the Eclectics, May 7-26, [1923] (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Guild of American Painters, November 26-December 8, 1923 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings by American Artists of the 19th Century, February 1939 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
  - Bendann's Art Galleries, 105 E. Baltimore Street, Baltimore, MD (Box 2)
    - Baltimore in the year 1896, 1896 (Box 2, Reel unfilmed)
  - Berlin Photographic Company, 305 Madison Ave., New York City (Box 2)
    - Memorial Loan Exhibition of the Works of Robert Frederick Blum, 1913 (Box 2, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pictures Painted by Stephen Haweis in the South Sea Islands, Melanesia, Polynesia, 1915 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings, Water Colors, and Etchings by Anne Goldthwaite, with an introduction by Martin Birnbaum, 1915 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Sculpture by Paul Manship, with an introduction by Martin Birnbaum, February 15-March 8, 1916 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings and Drawings by David Karfunkle, with an introduction by Martin Birnbaum, 1916 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Original Block Prints and Wood Engravings, May 1-31, 1916 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings by James Weiland, February 1-21, 1917 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
  - Bordighera (Box 2)
    - Second International Exhibition of American Painting, March 1-31, 1953 (Box 2, Reel unfilmed)
  - Boston Art Club, 270 Dartmouth St., Boston, Mass. (Box 2)
    - Recent Paintings by Emma Fordyce MacRae (Mrs. Homer F. Swift), January 19-February 6 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Water Color Drawings by John Singer Sargent and Edward Darley Boit, March 25-April 10, 1909 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
  - Boston Athenaeum (Box 2)
    - Fourth Exhibition in the Gallery of the Boston Athenaeum, 1830 (Box 2, Reel unfilmed)
    - Seventh Exhibition in the Gallery of the Boston Athenaeum, 1833 (Box 2, Reel unfilmed)
  - Boston Camera Club, 50 Broomfield St., Boston, Mass. (Box 2)
    - Year Book, 1900 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Twelfth Annual Club Exhibition, April 4-14, 1900 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
  - Boston Society of Independent Artists, 30 Newbury St., Boston, Mass. (Box 2)
    - Twelfth Annual Exhibition, March 19-April 8, 1939 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
  - Bourgeois Galleries, 668 Fifth Ave., New York City (Box 2)
    - Paintings and Drawings by Emile Branchard, October 11-November 1, 1919 (Box 2, Reel 4858)
    - Paintings, Etchings, Lithographs & Wood-Cuts by C.R.W. Nevinson of London, England, Introduction by C. Lewis Hind, November 10 - December 4 (Box 2, Reel 4858)